[
    {
        "question": "How is the market supply curve calculated?",
        "a": "multiplying each producer’s supply curves weighted by size",
        "b": "adding average total costs for each producer at each price",
        "c": "multiplying each producer’s supply curves vertically",
        "d": "adding each producer’s supply curves horizontally",
        "e": "multiplying marginal and average cost at each price",
        "correct_answer": "d"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following factors would NOT cause a shift in the supply curve for gasoline?",
        "a": "The supply of crude oil decreases.",
        "b": "The price of gasoline increases.",
        "c": "Labor costs decrease.",
        "d": "The price of crude oil increases.",
        "e": "The price of gasoline is expected to increase in the future.",
        "correct_answer": "b"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following changing factors does NOT shift the supply curve?",
        "a": "rising input prices",
        "b": "the price of related goods",
        "c": "improving technology",
        "d": "consumer expectations",
        "e": "falling number of sellers",
        "correct_answer": "b"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following rules is articulated in the law of supply?",
        "a": "A supply curve must slope upwards.",
        "b": "A supply curve must run horizontally.",
        "c": "A supply curve must be tangential to the equilibrium price axis.",
        "d": "A supply curve must increase exponentially.",
        "e": "A supply curve must cross the horizontal axis.",
        "correct_answer": "a"
    },
    {
        "question": "What assumption undergirds the interactions of the supply and demand curves?",
        "a": "All variables besides price are unchanged.",
        "b": "The value of money always rises.",
        "c": "Market surplus is positive.",
        "d": "Demand and price are negatively correlated.",
        "e": "Supply and price have a positive correlation.",
        "correct_answer": "a"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the law of supply?",
        "a": "As the price of a good increases, producers will sell more.",
        "b": "As the price of a good decreases, demand will increase.",
        "c": "As the price of a good increases, demand decreases.",
        "d": "As the price of a good decreases, producers will sell more.",
        "e": "As demand increases, producers will sell more.",
        "correct_answer": "a"
    },
    {
        "question": "If tortillas become 20% more expensive, what happens in the market for bread?",
        "a": "Supply decreases.",
        "b": "Quantity decreases.",
        "c": "Demand increases.",
        "d": "Equilibrium quantity falls.",
        "e": "Price decreases.",
        "correct_answer": "c"
    },
    {
        "question": "Sam has started to sell soap on Etsy, then realizes that it is a very competitive market. At what point does Sam stop supplying?",
        "a": "Large firms force him out of the market.",
        "b": "He makes zero economic profit.",
        "c": "His profit does not cover his manufacturing costs.",
        "d": "He can earn more by supplying another good instead.",
        "e": "The government limits his production.",
        "correct_answer": "d"
    },
    {
        "question": "If prices for a good are high, a producer is MOST likely to",
        "a": "leave the market",
        "b": "hire more staff",
        "c": "cut working hours",
        "d": "sell other products",
        "e": "automate production",
        "correct_answer": "b"
    },
    {
        "question": "How are quantity supplied and price related?",
        "a": "exponentially",
        "b": "positively",
        "c": "ambiguously",
        "d": "negatively",
        "e": "inversely",
        "correct_answer": "b"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the definition of “quantity supplied”?",
        "a": "the amount produced by sellers",
        "b": "minimizing deadweight loss",
        "c": "maximizing seller profit",
        "d": "the amount received by consumers",
        "e": "the maximum amount that is possible to produce",
        "correct_answer": "a"
    },
    {
        "question": "How does the market for peanut butter change when the price of its complement, jelly, falls?",
        "a": "Equilibrium quantity decreases.",
        "b": "Quantity demanded increases.",
        "c": "Quantity supplied increases.",
        "d": "Equilibrium price increases.",
        "e": "Quantity supplied decreases.",
        "correct_answer": "b"
    },
    {
        "question": "What variable is on the horizontal axis of a supply curve?",
        "a": "opportunity cost of all producers",
        "b": "quantity produced",
        "c": "price",
        "d": "quantity desired",
        "e": "total quantity sold",
        "correct_answer": "b"
    },
    {
        "question": "What relationship does a supply curve state?",
        "a": "Quantity supplied is negatively related to elasticity.",
        "b": "Supply is negatively related to price.",
        "c": "Equilibrium quantity is negatively related to price.",
        "d": "Quantity supplied is positively related to price.",
        "e": "Equilibrium quantity is positively related to opportunity cost.",
        "correct_answer": "d"
    },
    {
        "question": "How is the market supply curve calculated?",
        "a": "summing the prices of the producers’ supply horizontally",
        "b": "multiplying producers’ quantity supplied",
        "c": "multiplying consumer and producer surplus",
        "d": "adding producer’s quantity supplied",
        "e": "adding demand curves vertically",
        "correct_answer": "d"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following statements is NOT true of a competitive market at equilibrium?",
        "a": "Society receives the maximum benefit.",
        "b": "Buyers and sellers are satisfied.",
        "c": "Total surplus is maximized.",
        "d": "The outcome is Pareto efficient.",
        "e": "Firms earn profits equal to producer surplus.",
        "correct_answer": "e"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following statements BEST describes equilibrium?",
        "a": "One force is always more dominant than others.",
        "b": "All forces in a system are balanced.",
        "c": "There are no measurable externalities that impact the system.",
        "d": "All forces are measurable and quantifiable.",
        "e": "The system is in a constant state of flux.",
        "correct_answer": "b"
    },
    {
        "question": "If market price exceeds equilibrium price, market price will decline. What factor explains this correlation?",
        "a": "government intervention",
        "b": "excess supply",
        "c": "a lack of Pareto efficiency",
        "d": "excess demand",
        "e": "deadweight loss",
        "correct_answer": "b"
    },
    {
        "question": "Assume that the oil market is in equilibrium. What information does the price of oil communicate?",
        "a": "marginal cost per unit of oil",
        "b": "relative elasticity of oil supply",
        "c": "consumer surplus for the oil market",
        "d": "ease of entry into the market",
        "e": "value that buyers place on oil",
        "correct_answer": "e"
    },
    {
        "question": "A car manufacturing company notices that many consumers are motivated by environmental concerns, so they start to produce EVs. What factor influenced this shift?",
        "a": "tastes",
        "b": "expectations",
        "c": "input changes",
        "d": "technology",
        "e": "competition",
        "correct_answer": "a"
    },
    {
        "question": "How will the vaccine market be impacted if more producers enter the market?",
        "a": "quantity of vaccines produced will remain the same",
        "b": "demand for vaccines will decrease",
        "c": "supply of vaccines will increase",
        "d": "price of vaccines will increase",
        "e": "elasticity of supply of vaccines will decrease",
        "correct_answer": "c"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following inputs does a fashion company NOT require?",
        "a": "machinery",
        "b": "labor",
        "c": "leather",
        "d": "real estate",
        "e": "taxes",
        "correct_answer": "e"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which benefit naturally arises from competitive market equilibrium?",
        "a": "Everyone is allocated sufficient resources to survive.",
        "b": "A competitive market will never produce negative externalities.",
        "c": "A competitive market in equilibrium cannot be shifted.",
        "d": "The market benefit of the producer and consumer is maximized.",
        "e": "At competitive market equilibrium, there is no need for fiat currency.",
        "correct_answer": "d"
    },
    {
        "question": "If Joe is willing to pay $10 for a game ticket and the price is $20, what is his consumer surplus?",
        "a": "$10",
        "b": "$30",
        "c": "-$30",
        "d": "-$10",
        "e": "$0",
        "correct_answer": "e"
    },
    {
        "question": "How is information conveyed in perfectly competitive markets?",
        "a": "auction",
        "b": "surplus",
        "c": "opportunity costs",
        "d": "consumer tastes",
        "e": "price",
        "correct_answer": "e"
    },
    {
        "question": "Where can equilibrium be found on an economic diagram?",
        "a": "where consumer surplus is maximized",
        "b": "where the supply curve is tangent to the demand curve",
        "c": "where supply and demand curves intersect",
        "d": "where no deadweight loss occurs",
        "e": "where producers receive all the surplus",
        "correct_answer": "c"
    },
    {
        "question": "What change results if input prices of gasoline decrease?",
        "a": "Producer revenue will decrease.",
        "b": "Quantity produced will increase.",
        "c": "Price will increase.",
        "d": "Total quantity consumed will decrease.",
        "e": "Consumer surplus will decrease.",
        "correct_answer": "b"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following events would cause the supply curve to shift leftwards?",
        "a": "The input costs of the product decrease.",
        "b": "Suppliers expect prices to rise in a month.",
        "c": "An unexpected economic shock leads to a spike in demand.",
        "d": "Equilibrium price is forecasted to decrease.",
        "e": "Consumer surplus increases.",
        "correct_answer": "b"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following statements CORRECTLY describes market equilibrium?",
        "a": "There is only one equilibrium point in a market.",
        "b": "Market equilibrium is never Pareto efficient.",
        "c": "Suppliers have an incentive to charge more at equilibrium.",
        "d": "Equilibrium does not always exist in a market.",
        "e": "Equilibrium ensures all consumers and producers are equal.",
        "correct_answer": "a"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following events would NOT shift the supply curve for gasoline?",
        "a": "More suppliers enter the market.",
        "b": "Crude oil prices decrease.",
        "c": "Prices of gas are expected to rise in the future.",
        "d": "The price of gasoline rises.",
        "e": "A new self-service system is invented.",
        "correct_answer": "d"
    }
]

